Mauricio González Araya

San José, Costa Rica Cellphone: +50687075176 Email: mauriciogonzalez@pm.me

Driven professional with broad technical skill set, very strong attention to detail, and over 10 years of experience in front-end and back-end web development. Able to multitask and juggle multiple pressing projects simultaneously. On top of the latest trends and technologies.

SKILLS

Ruby (Rails, RSpec, Capybara)
PHP (Laravel, Wordpress, PHPUnit)
Databases (MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, MS SQL, PostgreSQL)
Javascript (Vanilla, React, Redux, Vue)
Web (HTML, CSS, Responsive design, hybrid mobile apps)
API development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INCLUIT

Cordoba, Argentina December 2022 – Present

Software Developer – EVO SECURITY

Eliminate credential sharing, establish powerful administrative permissions, mass deploy login security for your customers, and meet insurance and compliance requirements with an Identity and Access Management (IAM) platform purpose-built for MSPs.

Technologies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React/Vue, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS, Kubernetes.

- Help refactor the API by moving it out of legacy.
- Improve the platform. Introduce best practices.
- Refactored the Authentication area of the application and removed the dependency of PrivacyIdea, saving around 3.000 USD a month for the company.
- Developed a new feature to create JustInTime accounts on MS Entra for our MSP Technicians.
- Currently working a new feature to expand our offering and cater to larger enterprises and resellers, we need to introduce multi-partner support, allowing a single PSA instance to manage multiple partner organizations seamlessly.

ENCORA

Heredia, CR January 2019 – December 2022

Software Developer – BUGCROWD

Help design and maintain the platform by working with our product team and both internal and external stakeholders to provide an engineering perspective. Our ultimate goal being to build a platform that connects researchers around the world with companies to help all of us be more secure.

Technologies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS.

- Improve the platform for our amazing internal teams, such as the Application Security Engineers who review and test vulnerabilities.
- Helped refactor our API to a more succinct approach that allow us to cut versions quicker.
- Developed several integrations: Jira and incoming/outgoing webhooks.
- Gave weekly tech talks for our CR team on any technology we were all interested in getting better at.
- Leads the Ruby interviews for Encora and participate in the ones conducted by the client directly with US candidates
- Onboarding of junior developers
- Currently working on building a SCIM proxy service for customer leveraging SSO
- Currently working on a new integration for external issues created in our platform
- API developer lead

ORA INTERACTIVE

Chicago, IL June 2016 – December 2018

Web Developer

Continuous implementation and maintenance of native IOS projects such as: PonyApp.

Technologies: PHP/Laravel, MySQL and Angular/Ember hosted on AWS

- Developed and improved REST APIs.
- Made sure the API was JSONAPI compliant.
- Kept the Swagger driven API documentation up to date.
- Strove to always have a very high coverage percentage of the PHPUNIT testing.

OFFICESPACE SOFTWARE

San José, Costa Rica/New York, NY December 2014 – May 2016

Software Developer

Developed and maintained the product which is a complete solution for the allocation and management of company workspaces.

Technologies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React, MariaDB

- Write functional, unit, and integration tests for application quality assurance.
- Followed standard software development life cycle processes and participated in code reviews, building and executing unit test plans, and software packaging and deployment.
- Researched and recommended new technologies to support application development.

BLUE FOUNTAIN MEDIA October 2013 – November 2014 New York, NY

Web Developer

I was part of a remote distributed team of developers (USA, Argentina, Portugal and Costa Rica) that developed consumer based features.

Technologies: PHP, Wordpress, Magento, Drupal, CSS, Javascript, HTML.

- Contributed to writing code and SEO.
- Implemented PSD to HTML website layouts.
- Monitored traffic usage to determine which areas needed to be modified for increased visibility and recognition.
- Introduced new plug-ins and extensions to make the website more usable and interactive.
- Developed new website features and seeks out existing solutions to meet client needs..

CRITICAL MASS October 2008 – September 2013

San José, Costa Rica

Web Developer/Tech Lead

Managed and contributed to the execution of projects for accounts like Clorox, Nissan and Best Buy. These projects involved content entry, animated banners, front and back end development.

- Assisted with managing a team of 15+ peers. Direct contact with clients and provided technical estimations, interviewing and project oversight.
- Responsible for all stages of website creations for clientele. From initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management of web applications.
- Lead project teams in the delivery of client requirements and ensured project deliverables were met.
- Promoted to Senior Developer after 6 months.
- Employee of the year.

FORMAL EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL

Heredia, Costa Rica

Bachelor of Science: Systems Engineering

UNIVERSIDAD DE BARCELONA/OBS

Barcelona, Spain

Master in Business Information Security

OTHER

Scrum Master

Comptia Sec+

eLearnSecurity Junior Penetration Tester (EJPT)

Languages

Spanish (native)
English (advanced)

Currently pursuing

Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)

Linux Foundation Certified System Administrator (LFCS)